// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the meaning of SEIRI in 5S techniques?",
    //immg:"img1",
    answer: "Removes unnecessary items",
    options: [
      "Identifies storage",
      "Clean and inspects",
      "Operating procedures",
      "Removes unnecessary items"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is the use of try square shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img2",
    answer: "To check the squareness",
    options: [
      "To check the flatness",
      "To check the squareness",
      "To mark lines at 90o", 
      "To set the workpiece at right angle"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is the use of groove provided on the either side of a vee-block?",
    
    answer: "Holding clamps",
    options: [
      "For appearance",
      "For reducing the weight",
      "To reduce bearing surface",
      "Holding clamps"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which metal property can be drawn into the wire without any rupture?",
   // immg:"img4",
    answer: "Ductility",
    options: [
      "Ductility",
      "Tenacity",
      "Elasticity",
      "Malleability"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Why slots are provided in the slotted angle plate?",
    answer: "For job clamping",
    options: [
      "For job clamping",
      "For easy handling",
      "For reducing the weight",
      "For better appearance"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which metal property can resist the effect of tensile forces without any rupture?",
    //immg:"img6",
    answer: "Tenacity",
    options: [
      "Ductility",
      "Tenacity",
      "Elasticity",
      "Malleability"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What is the name of the parallel block shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img7",
    answer: "Adjustable parallel block",
    options: [
      "Solid parallel block",
      "Tenon parallel block",
      "Angular parallel block",
      "Adjustable parallel block"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which marking media is applied in rough forgings and castings?",
    //immg:"img8",
    answer: "White wash",
    options: [
      "White wash",
      "Prussian blue",
      "Copper Sulphate",
      "Cellulose lacquer"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which metal cutting saw is used for cutting different profiles?",
   // immg:"img9",    
    answer: "Contour band saw",
    options: [
      "Power saw",
      "Circular saw",
      "Contour band saw",
      "Horizontal band saw"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which metal property permits no permanent distortion on before breaking?",
    
    answer: "Brittleness",
    options: [
      "Tenacity",
      "Hardness",
      "Brittleness",
      "Toughness"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Why surface plates are made of up of stress-relieved, good quality cast iron?",
   // immg:"img11",
    answer: "To prevent distortion",
    options: [
      "To prevent corrosion",
      "To prevent breaking",
      "To prevent distortion",
      "To prevent thermal expansion"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 12,
    question: "What is the main advantage of adjustable parallel block?",
    
    answer: "To set different height",
    options: [
      "To set different angle",
      "To set different depth",
      "To set different length",
      "To set different height"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which part of an universal surface gauge is used to set scriber exactly at the required position?",
    
    answer: "Fine adjustment screw",
    options: [
      "Snug",
      "Guide Pin",
      "Rocker arm",
      "Fine adjustment screw"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which metal cutting saw is used to cut large cross section area? ",
  //  immg:"img14",
    answer: "Circular saw",
    options: [
      "Power saw",
      "Contour saw",
      "Circular saw",
      "Horizontal band saw"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which metal property can with stand shock or impact?",
    
    answer: "Toughness",
    options: [
      "Tenacity",
      "Hardness",
      "Brittleness",
     "Toughness"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Why are ribs provided in the angle plate?",
     //immg:"img16",
    answer: "Prevents distortion",
    options: [
      "Provide flatness",
      "Prevents distortion",
      "Provides squareness",
      "Support the machined surface"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which type of  V block is shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img17",
    answer: "Double level single groove",
    options: [
      "Single level single groove",
      "Single level double groove",
      "Double level single groove",
      "Double level double groove"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Which part of the universal surface gauge holds the scriber?",
    
    answer:"Snug",
    options: [
      "Snug",
      "Guide Pin",
      "Rocker arm",
      "Fine adjustment screw"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which metal property is beneficial for melting?",
    
    answer:"Fusibility",
    options: [
      "Fusibility",
      "Specific gravity",
      "Conductivity",
      "Structure"
    ]
  },
        {
    numb: 20,
    question: "What is the name of the metal-cutting saws shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img20",
    answer:"Circular saw",
    options: [
      "Power saw",
      "Horizontal band - saw",
      "Circular saw",
      "Contour saw"
    ]
  },  
  
             {
    numb: 21,
    question: "Which material is used to manufacture Grade A V blocks?",
    
    answer:"High quality steel",
    options: [
      "Tool steel",
      "Carbon steel",
      "High quality steel",
      "Closely grained cast iron"
    ]
  },
                 
        {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Which metal is a good conductor of heat and electricity?",
    //immg:"img22",
    answer:"Copper",
    options: [
      "Cast iron",
      "Mild steel",
      "Copper",
      "Wrought iron"
    ]
  },  
     {
    numb: 23,
    question: "What is the specific gravity for aluminium?",
   // immg:"img23",
    answer:"2.6kg/cm3",
    options: [
      "9kg/cm3",
      "2.8kg/cm3",
      "2.6kg/cm3",
      "8.5kg/cm3"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which mechanical property of metal has the ability to withstand wear and abrasion?",
   // immg:"img24",
    answer: "Hardness",
    options: [
      "Toughness",
      "Hardness",
      "Brittleness",
     "Malleability"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "Which mechanical property of metal extends in all directions without rupturing during hammering?",
    
    answer: "Malleability",
    options: [
      "Malleability",
      "Ductility",
      "Fusibility",
     "Elasticity"
    ]
  },        
               {
    numb: 26,
    question: "Which is used for locating the holes in the assembly shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img26",
    answer:"Dowel",
    options: [
      "Dowel",
      "Screw",
      "Bolt",
      "Nut"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 27,
    question: "What is the reading of the vernier bevel protractor shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img27",
    answer: "41o 50min",
    options: [
      "18o 50min",
      "41o 50min",
      "50o 50min",
     "58o 50min"
    ]
  },
          {
    numb: 28,
    question: "What type of operation is carried out in a gang drilling machine?",
    //immg:"img28",
    answer: "Successive operation of drilling",
    options: [
      "Idle operation",
      "Repeated operation of drilling",
      "Continuous milling operation",
     "Successive operation of drilling"
    ]
  },

      {
    numb: 29,
    question: "Which is an integral part of the stock in vernier bevel protractor? ",
    
    answer: "Dial",
    options: [
      "Disc",
      "Dial",
      "Blade",
     "Main scale"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 30,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as X shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img30",
    answer: "Anvil",
    options: [
      "Anvil",
      "Thimble",
      "Spindle",
     "Spindle lock"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 31,
    question: "What is the accuracy of a metric outside micrometer?",
    //immg:"img36",
    answer: "0.01 mm",
    options: [
      "0.01 mm",
      "0.001 mm",
      "0.002 mm",
     "0.02 mm"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 32,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as X shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img32",
    answer: "Drill chuck",
    options: [
      "Drill chuck",
      "Feed handle",
      "Driving motor",
     "Depth gaguge and stop"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 33,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked as X shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img33",
    answer: "Fine adjusting slide",
    options: [
      "Beam",
      "Main scale",
      "Fine adjusting nut",
     "Fine adjusting slide"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 34,
    question: "What is the name of the drilling machine shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img34",
    answer: "Pillar drilling machine",
    options: [
      "Pillar drilling machine",
      "Gang drilling machine",
      "Bench drilling machine",
     "Radial drilling machine"
    ]
  }
    ,
     {
    numb: 35,
    question: "How can a wide range of depth be measured using a depth micrometer?",
    
    answer: "cast iron",
    options: [
      "lengthly sleeve",
      "lengthly spindle",
      "adjustable base",
     "Use of extension rods"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 36,
    question: "Which part of the drilling machine is used to achieve set a different speed?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Stepped pulley",
    options: [
      "Flat pulley",
      "Jockey pulley",
      "Stepped pulley",
     "Fast and loose pulley"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 37,
    question: "Identify the type of drilling machine whose spindle head is moved towards or away from the column.",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Radial drilling machine",
    options: [
      "Pillar drilling machine",
      "Gang drilling machine",
      "Radial drilling machine",
     "Sensitive bench drilling machine"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 38,
    question: "What is the reading of vernier caliper with inch graduations shown in the figure?",
   immg:"img38",
    answer: "1.459",
    options: [
      "1.068",
      "1.459",
      "1.418",
     "1.409"
    ]
  },
        {
    numb: 39,
    question: "What is termed as the quantity of matter contained in a body?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Mass",
    options: [
      "Density",
      "Volume",
      "Mass",
     "Specific gravity"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 40,
    question: "What is called mass per unit volume of a substances?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Density",
    options: [
      "Mass",
      "Weight",
      "Density",
     "Volume"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 41,
    question: "What is the ratio of power output to power input?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Efficiency",
    options: [
      "Work",
      "Energy",
      "Efficiency",
     "Acceleration"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 42,
    question: "How many watts for 1 horse power in British System",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "746 watts",
    options: [
      "726 watts",
      "736 watts",
      "746 watts",
     "756 watts"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 43,
    question: "What is the S.I unit of heat?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Joule",
    options: [
      "Calorie",
      "Joule",
      "Centigrade heat unit",
     "British thermal unit"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 44,
    question: "What is known for the temperature at which any solid melts into liquid?",
   // immg:"img36",
    answer: "Melting point",
    options: [
      "Boiling point",
      "Melting point",
      "Latent heat of fusion",
     "Latent heat of vaporisation"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 45,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
    immg:"img45",
    answer: "Steel",
    options: [
      "Lead",
      "Steel",
      "Glass",
     "Porcelain"
    ]
  },
         {
    numb: 46,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
     immg:"img46",
    answer: "glass",
    options: [
      "lead",
      "glass",
      "wood",
     "steel"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 47,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol material?",
    immg:"img47",
    answer: "concrete",
    options: [
      "steel",
      "wood",
      "glass",
     "concrete"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 48,
    question: "What is the trimmed size of A4 sheet?",
   // immg:"img48",
    answer: "210 x 297",
    options: [
      "841 x 1189",
      "594 x 841",
      "210 x 297",
     "148 x 210"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 49,
    question: "Compass used to draw for....",
    
    answer: "circle",
    options: [
      "rectangle",
      "square",
      "circle",
     "traingle"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 50,
    question: "Identify the name of prism?",
      immg:"img50",
    answer: "Hexagonal prism",
    options: [
      "Square prism",
      "Pentagonal prism",
      "Triangular prism",
     "Hexagonal prism"
    ]
  },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];
